The Clearing is a drama, mystery, thriller film directed by Pieter Jan Brugge.
When affluent executive Wayne Hayes is kidnapped by a disgruntled employee and held for ransom in a forest,
Wayne’s wife is forced to reckon with the FBI agents as they negotiate with the kidnapper.
Wayne Hayes, played by Robert Redford.
Eileen Hayes, played by Helen Mirren.
Arnold Mack, played by Willem Dafoe.
Tim Hayes, played by Alessandro Nivola.
Agent Ray Fuller, played by Matt Craven.
Jill Hayes, played by Melissa Sagemiller.
The Clearing is a 2004 American crime thriller film and the
directorial debut of film producer Pieter Jan Brugge.
The film is loosely based on the real-life kidnapping and murder of Dutch
businessman Gerrit Jan Heijn that took place in the Netherlands in 1987.
The screenplay was written by Justin Haythe.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship,
ransom, kidnapping, hostage, psychopath.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.